Ritali Ghosh

Graduate Student, Indian Institute of Science

I am a Graduate Student at the Indian Institute of Science (IISc), Bengaluru, India. My research interests are in astrophysical fluid dynamics using computational techniques and cosmological simulations of galaxy formation. I am presently working on idealized simulations to understand the environmental influences on various components of the galaxy undergoing ram-pressure stripping.



Experience

2021-08 - Senior Research Fellow

Present Indian Institute of Science, Bengaluru

2019-08 - Junior Research Fellow

2021-07 Indian Institute of Science, Bengaluru



Education

2015-06 - Master of Science, Physics

2017-05 University of Calcutta, Kolkata, India

2012-06 - Bachelor of Science, Physics Bethune College, Kolkata, India



Publications

Ram pressure stripping in clusters: Gravity can bind the ISM but not the CGM, 2023 Submitted to MNRAS

Ritali Ghosh, Alankar Dutta, Prateek Sharma

Beyond profiles: Using log-normal distributions to model the multiphase circumgalactic medium, 2023

Submitted to MNRAS (arXiv:2310.03717)

Alankar Dutta, Mukesh Singh Bisht, Prateek Sharma, *Ritali Ghosh*, Manami Roy and Biman B. Nath



Talks and Research Visits

Conference Talk, Astronomical Society of India Meeting, ASI 2024

01 Feb - 04 Feb 2024

organized by the Astronomical Society of India (ASI) at IISc Bangalore, India

Seminar Talk, Universitäts-Sternwarte München, Germany

November 2023

At Weekly CAST Meeting, USM, Muenchen, Germany

Conference Talk, Modelling of Multiphase Astrophysical Media, Aspenstein Castle at Lake Kochel, Bavaria

30 May - 02 June 2023

organized by Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics, Garching, Germany

Conference Talk, GALFLOWS 2023: A National Workshop on Galactic inflows and outflows on all Scales



Contact

 Room D2-04, Department of Physical Science, Indian Institute of Science,
Bengaluru, India – 560012

(+91) 7278335730

ritalighosh@iisc.ac.in

0000-0001-8643-7104

S @RRitali



Technical Profile

- C/C++, Python, Fortran, LATEX
- Tools/Codes used: PLUTO, ParaView, Cloudy
- Ability to Work in a Team
- Critical thinking and problem solving



Languages

English (proficient)

Hindi (native speaker)

Bengali

German (A1 level)

02 - 05 February 2023

organized by Inter University Campus of Astronomy and Astrophysics (IUCAA), Pune

Conference Talk, What matter(s) around galaxies 2022: Connecting the dots between the CGM and the larger-scale environment

12 - 16 September 2022

organized by Università Milano-Bicocca at Champoluc, Aosta Valley, Italy

Seminar Talk, Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics, Garching, Germany

September 2022

MPA Cosmology Seminar, Garching, Germany

Seminar Talk, Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia, INAF, Italy

September 2022

at INAF, the Italian National Institute for Astrophysics, Padua, Italy

Poster Presentation, Astronomical Society of India Meeting, ASI 2022

March 2022

organized by the Astronomical Society of India (ASI) at IIT Roorkee, India

KITP Program: Fundamentals of Gaseous Halos (Online Attendee)

January 2022

organized by Kavli Institute for Theoretical Physics, Santa Barbara, California, USA



Academic Awards

National Level Qualified Examinations

- Qualified GATE Fellowship 2019
- Qualified UGC-JRF NET December 2018
- Qualified JEST 2019

Academic Achievements and Scholarships

- Ranked 5th in University of Calcutta, M.Sc. Batch 2015-17
- DST-INSPIRE Scholarship 2012-2017
- Mamraj Agarwal Rashtriya Puraskar, 2012 (felicitated for scoring 96.6% in CBSE Class XII Exams, 2012 by the then Governor of West Bengal, India)
- Certificate of Merit in Mathematics 2012 (for being in top 0.1% of All India Senior School Certificate Exam, 2012 in Mathematics (Score: 100%))



Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistantship, PH 365, Galaxies and the Interstellar Medium, Joint Astronomy and Astrophysics Program (JAP), IISc

January 2023 — May 2023

Teaching Assistantship, PH 363, Introduction to Fluid Mechanics and Plasma Physics, Joint Astronomy and Astrophysics Program (JAP), IISc

August 2021 — December 2021



References

Prof. Prateek Sharma, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India

prateek@iisc.ac.in

Dr. Max Gronke, Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics, Garching, Germany

maxbg@mpa-garching.mpg.de